Guide to the Subject Files Reference Collection, 1859-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Subject Files Reference collection 1859-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
2.5 linear feet Extent: approx. 2,000 Items
The Subject Files Reference Collection contains files concerning a variety of subjects common to academic institutions, such as institutional history and governance, diversity, parking, statistics, and so forth. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
RL.01879
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Subject Files Reference Collection was compiled by University Archives staff from a variety of sources.
Collection Overview
The collection contains files concerning a variety of subjects common to academic institutions. The materials present include memoranda, lists and compilations, brochures, news clippings, articles about the University, and manuscripts. Major subjects include university history and governance, tuition and financial aid, pluralism, and transportation and parking. Among the notable subjects is a 1975 fact-finding trip to China led by Mrs. Terry Sanford.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.)--History -- 19th century; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.)--History -- 20th century
Related Material
Commencement Collection (for visitors to campus)
Duke University Archives
Newspapers Collection (articles about Duke)
Duke University Archives
University Policies Reference Collection (honor code)
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Crime (Box 1)
  - Crime, frauds and imposters
  - Crime, sexual assault and rape
  - Duke authors, 1984
  - Duke in the media: articles about Duke, list
  - Duke in the media: articles about Duke, 1920-1929
  - Duke in the media: articles about Duke, 1930-1939
  - Duke in the media: articles about Duke, 1940-1949
  - Duke in the media: articles about Duke, 1950-1959
  - Duke in the media: articles about Duke, 1960-1969
  - Duke in the media: articles about Duke, 1970-1979
  - Duke in the media: articles about Duke, 1980-1989 (Box 2)
  - Duke in the media: articles about Duke, 1990-1999
  - Duke in the media: articles about Duke, 2000-
  - Duke in the media: Duke in books
  - Duke in the media: films and television (2 folders)
  - Globalization
  - Globalization: China
  - Globalization: China trip, 1975
  - Globalization: China trip, 1975: China Encounter [newspaper]
  - Globalization: China trip, 1975: clippings and news releases
  - Globalization: China trip, 1975: participants' notes and reports (2 folders)
  - Globalization: India
  - Governance: Academic Council, 1971, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Governance: Aims of the University and mission statements, 1903-
  - Governance: Bylaws, 1859-
  - Governance: Charter, 1975-; see also History and Government of Duke University
  - Governance: Clippings, 1969-
  - Governance: History and Government of Duke University, 1931, 1936, 1952, 1955, 1958
  - Governance: The Troika, [1969]
  - History and tradition: Class gifts
  - History and tradition: Commencement, Bibles at
  - History and tradition: Duke and the Methodist Church, 1957-
  - History and tradition: Duke history
  - History and tradition: Duke statistics, circa 1962-1996
  - History and tradition: Ghosts and ghost stories
  - History and tradition: Myths
  - History and tradition: Student Education Project, 1997
  - History and tradition: Traditions
  - Honorary degrees, lists (Box 4)
  - Humor
  - Intellectual life
  - Playboy
  - Pluralism: Duke's Vision, 1989-1991
  - Pluralism: Political correctness, circa 1989-1994
  - Politics: national, state, local, circa 1960-
  - Politics: Duke connections in Congress, 1986-1987
  - Technology and computing: clippings, circa 1980- (2 folders)
  - Technology and computing: Duchess [computer program], 1978-1982
  - Technology and computing: Duke University Computer Kamp (DUCK), 1981-1985
  - Technology and computing: Memos, brochures, etc., 1954-
  - Tobacco (Box 5)
  - Tours and tour guides, 1964-
  - Transportation and parking: clippings
  - Transportation and parking: committees, circa 1989-2000
  - Transportation and parking: cycling
  - Transportation and parking: maps, circa 1972-
  - Transportation and parking: memos and policies, circa 1967-
  - Tuition and financial aid: memoranda, receipts, brochures, etc., 1932-
  - Tuition and financial aid: clippings, 1962-
  - University cooperation, 1935-
  - Weather